here is the wing
thank you so much you're welcome thank you
I think it's right over there
go straight and turn right
clear room and you can see the staff here
awful thank you so much
thank you
that the immigration process was very easy
it's incredibly modern
heartlessly clean
this is one of the best
first impressions so far of a country that we've had
clean fast
affordable and easy to use
welcome to Chengdu
just about enough space I think got it
hello everybody and
good morning from
Bangkok Thailand Today
we're heading to a country that neither of us
know very much about
we only have preconceptions that we have been taught
from western media from western education
we know basically zero about where we're heading to
but nonetheless it's a new country
it's the beginning of a new adventure
and we're very very excited
to head to China
super excited
also a little bit nervous like I'm not gonna lie
first time going to China
and yeah
let's just get on a plane and see what it's like
we're all checked in and we are ready
to fly to Chengdu
very very exciting
right you guys I hope you can hear me
we're just about to arrive at Chengdu and it seems like
a lot of Chengdu might have
burning season still going because you can see
dotted along the
landscape sort of
fires burning here and there
I'm not really sure if there's a
burning season or if that's just a
usual situation in Chengdu
maybe that the farmers are doing
I don't know but it looks
very interesting and so different as well from
what the the landscape that we are usually used to so
both of us are very excited
um a little bit nervous I'm not gonna lie
because obviously it's our first time to China
neither of us speak
Chinese or we Chinese so it's gonna be
I think challenging but very very beautiful
welcome to Tianfu International Airport in Chengdu
China
I never thought that I would say that sentence
no
we're in mainland
we're in mainland China guys so
first time and
we're gonna be here for a couple weeks
we have a lot to learn we have a lot to explore
well
to get your immigration still
so we're not even sure if we're actually in yet
look
we'll see what happens
first impressions as well is it's really cold
so
it seems to be just like 20 degrees Celsius right now
and we just came from 39 degrees Celsius Bangkok so
19 degrees difference
I don't know I'm very cold
just just picked up our bags guys
I can barely even speak because of how excited I am
we have our stamp and we have just entered
and have our first couple of footsteps
in China
so yeah that's a pretty crazy we cannot believe this
next up we need to figure out
now we're going to take the metro
from here to where we want to stay we have no idea
where we're going what we're doing
this airport by the way Tianfu International
I believe it's quite new
it's incredibly modern
spotlessly clean and I have to say
that the immigration process was very easy
yeah that's what I wanted to say immigration was
relatively easy for us
the people spoke English
everything was fine we just had to fill out
a little card like this basically
which you have to carry afterwards with you
you presented
no questions asked just kind of where are you going
what are you doing and was it
yep we're in very very straightforward
quite literally took around 10 minutes and yeah
we're in China so let's go and figure out
how to take this metro
and how to work
everything
as we just downloaded before we left Bangkok
we downloaded
Alipay and a couple of other different things
so yeah we're gonna see how that all works
we're also on the look for a SIM card so
SIM card SIM card
a lot of things that we have to check
check off basically
so yeah let's go into China
welcome to Chengdu
I love it look at the pandas
now
we're gonna be documenting quite literally everything
for you guys just in case
you are also planning on coming to China
and you might be very confused like we are
so we're gonna try and take cash out
now I know cash is not typically widely used here
in China it's mostly Alipay and Wechat and a lot of
sort of QR code payment systems
digitalized payment systems
we're gonna try
and take some cash out and see if that's an option
for us
because we have heard that you can use cash in certain
circumstances
and we're not too sure if our Alipay works just yet
so
let's see if our visa works
online we read at sort of every ATM purposes
please pay attention to your surroundings
please make sure the surroundings are safe
before entering your password
oh it's giving instructions
please select the service entry withdrawal
please select or enter the amount take out
500 yuan
the transaction transaction is being processed
please wait
this is the most nerve working part
oh my gosh it's doing something
oh it's counting
working
I think it works
oh my God
I was so scared that we're not gonna be able to use it
it's working I think
very very cool
we have 500
Chinese Yuan
very very interesting looking currency that's for sure
amazing so first step of entering China complete
this is going a lot easier than I thought it would be
and we weren't even charged commission
there you go
so that's amazing
so believe it or not we have a SIM card now
sorted that out so that's another thing
off the checklist
very very easy unbelievably easy actually so far
and now we're making our way to the metro
so we need to take the metro to get into the center
yeah yeah yeah
yeah
yes I am oh
cool you know how to get to tango
center
the city
if you wanna go to the middle city you can go line 18
line 18 yeah we have some metro
yeah metro line
that's all we're looking for
yeah yeah and you can go to Chengdu Square
and when you at Chengdu Square is the middle of ST
Chengdu City and you can go anywhere from there
hmm
yes and South Railway Station
you need to transfer line one
from 19 to 91
so cool
and if you want to buy the air
the metro tickets yeah here is the way
oh thank you so much you're welcome
thank you
Alipay there yeah yeah yeah sure Alipay which I pay
or even credit card
nice
thank you
cash
yeah
okay cool thank you so much
I think it's right over there
go straight and turn
right
there is
a several small room
yeah it's clear room and you can see the staff there
oh thank you so much
have a nice day
really good English as well
this is one of the best
first impressions so far of a country that we've had
and
it's very interesting because the
general perception
of China in the west
I don't need to tell you
it's a overwhelmingly negative
let's put it that way from the media
and from a lot of other institutions so
this is the whole reason
why we decided to come to this country
because we wanted to see
exactly what it's like for ourselves
and we're already
getting on to a very positive
first experience so that's very interesting
gonna go over and buy some metro tickets
with the cash that we got out from the ATM
we still need to figure out what station
we need to change though
yeah true that's very nice
but we only know it in Chinese characters
so I don't know
I cannot read
it this one
let's see oh
it worked off
wow the lady had said that
it wasn't possible to play with Alipay
but we just played with Alipay
we just played with Alipay it was really easy
two tickets to Line 18
was really affordable too
super affordable at €2
30 for both of us nice
let's go and take the Chengdu Metro
for the very first time
surprisingly bilingual
I was really scared that we were gonna arrive and not
understand anything but it's like
just perfect you can really like reach pretty much
anything that is going on
and you don't even need a translator
I was really scared because
obviously it's difficult to access Google Translate
and that's like that
so I was like
I don't know if we're even
gonna manage to get somewhere
but
everything is boiling it's also in English so it's fun
yeah it's incredible it's
really really straightforward and easy
so nervous for no reason at all
kind of I feel literally at least so far
maybe there is gonna be a reason leader
where we're headed to is right here
small
south railway station of Chengdu
yeah guys this is the
Chengdu Metro incredibly incredibly clean
fast
affordable and easy to use
so there you go
let's see how long it takes
us to get from where we were to the
station that we want to go to
okay guys we're just transferring from
one line to the other line
and I do believe we need to go here to the
left side it's a little bit uh
it's not complicated
it's just I think difficult to understand
because obviously it's our first time
uh using the Metro lines here so
yeah we're sort of a little bit overwhelmed we need to
uh go all the way to rem them North Road
just here
and that's where we're gonna change into the No. 6
so that's the way it works by the way we did it wrong
we just bought a ticket
for uh one train but I believe
you can just buy the ticket for all of the trains
uh towards the end station that you need to
go to and then not get in and out of the street
of the station basically
so yeah just buy one ticket
get on a train
and that it's gonna do what they're doing
wow okay
apparently we're on the right path now
so we just need to basically find eggs today
but after 3 trains swapping between those three trains
I feel like we're on the right path
we're nearly there and we are ready to check in so
let's see where we end up
we're gonna go towards
Exit A
of wherever we are right now
and find
exactly where we need to go give you guys a room tour
of the accommodation that we're gonna be staying at
in Chengdu very very excited to have a bed
some nice AC maybe and also
head out for some food or we're gonna save that
for the next little video for you guys
we're gonna give you a nice room tour nonetheless
also if you guys are foreigners arriving into China
make sure to get a
description of the path that you have to take
in your own scriptures or in our case English
because if it wasn't wouldn't have been for the hostel
I think we would have been completely lost
we
just checked in so
our room exists
our accommodation exists everything exists
let's see what it's like
ta da
welcome to our room in Chengdu China
wow we're going to turn on dead lights
yeah
we need lights oh she turned it off here you go
okay welcome to our room
central
Chengdu China Sichuan wow
so this is our bathroom
it's kind of like an artsy hipster
type of a hostel type of situation going on here
but we do have a private room so that's nice
this is the bathroom it's actually very clean
tiling on the wall here that's kind of nice
then you do have
very nice looking shower
you've got like a rainfall head shower situation
there's me in the mirror
you also have
the usual sink
hair dryer etc etc
and oh we have a kettle
over there that's super nice
yes
two beds which is fine
we not sure if we can move them together but each one
is big enough to
kind of like two double beds actually
I like the lighting situation as well
it's pretty chill and mellow
did you open the window
no it was open
oh okay cool nice
so at least we have some airflow coming into the room
it looks like a really new AC
it looks like a brand new AC that's true this
hotel in general is kind of I think
relatively new
and that's what it looks like
it looks like it was only recently sort of
constructed together
and it has like like I said kind of like a hipster art
type of a vibe
like they just kind of put this board
wall together and made it into a lighting situation
the bed looks very very clean
and also soft
it's nice and soft too yeah it's a
lot of times we get these like really hard
beds that are
I don't know for my back
not so great
like unmanageable for my back so this one is really
nice and apparently there's also a washing machine and
a free gym which
which I would
like to have a look at
and then also what I want to say here in
Chengdu it really seems like
air quality is really really good very positive
um we actually came out of the m R t
and we took a deep breath in and it just
it felt really nice
and I actually I saw that beforehand on Google and
and I
didn't really want to believe it because I thought okay
there's gonna be
a lot of people a lot of um
traffic a lot of cars and so on
like the typical things
that you would think about when you think China but
not in this area
in this area you have
very nice air everything is very laid back
it's not crowded
it seems super beautiful outside
and the temperatures are actually nice as well
so I'm super happy
very true we were just talking about this outside
I think we made the right choice
with our first stop so Chengdu as our very first
city to experience China
I think if we picked Beijing or Shanghai
or one of these
very large mega cities
Chengdu is a very large city in itself
but it seems to be relatively
laid back in comparison to a lot of those other cities
it's also known as a Park City so there's plenty of
public spaces plenty of parks plenty of nature
when we were landing on the plane
how to look out the window
and all you could see was green
so yeah
there's plenty of beautiful nature around
for us to check out
which is our favorite
we're very excited to try some Chinese food
meet some Chinese locals
we already met some
today in the airport as you guys saw
so so far
the experience that we're having genuine is incredible
this is not us just putting this on
if we run into negative stuff
we're gonna share it with you guys as well
so keep that in mind
we're gonna be 100 percent honest to build this trip
AC works
I think so yeah
I just don't know what I can hear it
we don't even need an AC
I'm not used to this anymore
yeah that's very true
just turn it off
I don't know
it said yeah it's not that warm it's only like I think
roughly
18 well
so we just came from Bangkok where it's 37 to 38 to
sometimes 40 plus
coming here to Chengdu it's a breath of pressure
and yeah China
you are very positively surprising us so far
Alipay works incredibly well
it works with everything
we just paid for our room with Alipay
which I cannot understand
the app itself has
everything it has taxis it has
map function it has just
literally everything in one
I can also order food on there as you can order food
yeah so
it's kind of like a one size fits all
type of situation
it's made everything very streamlined for us so far
our whole experience
to be honest when we were lying in bed last night
before we came here
both of us were saying to each other
so scared we're not going to be able to use
anything that we're used to using
can't use things like
Google for example
you can't use a lot of the
regular apps that the western people are used to using
so we were like how are we gonna navigate around
we're gonna get lost
we're gonna get stuck we're gonna get
we're not gonna be able to take money out
we're not gonna be able to do any of these things
what we can
so we didn't really have to stress out for much
we took quite a bit of cash out as you saw
we took like 500
note I think and
we didn't use a single one of them yet
actually I thought that we would
run into issues immediately
and having to use cash basically
the second that we hit the Metro but
that was not the case
no need and yeah we have
had zero issues so far
other than us
just not understanding how the metro line
and how big the metro line is
that confused us a good bit
I'm not gonna lie
it's just because of the size of it and Chengdu is big
so we have a lot to get used to
and we have plenty more videos coming your way
where we are going to be
getting used to everything in China
over the next while
so I hope you guys
will tag along with us for that because yeah
we've got plenty of videos coming at you
super super excited
and also of course
a little bit nervous because a new country
a new language
a new culture
a lot of things to learn so yeah
I'm like very positively excited and positively nervous
yeah
we're literally in a country that our entire
literal entire part of the world tells
us never to go to
yeah and that is a pretty crazy feeling
and yeah we need to come to terms with that
and you're gonna hopefully join us as we
show you guys the real
sort of down toward version as to what this country is
what the people are like and what you can experience
but for now guys
my name is Luke
my name is Naomi
we are the two mod explorers
and this is your reminder to keep exploring
see you guys in the next China adventure
Shan Shan for watching
Shan Shan bye bye bye bye